<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title></title>
        <description></description>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
        <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2025 23:05:43 +0530</pubDate>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2025 23:05:43 +0530</lastBuildDate>
        <generator>Jekyll v4.3.3</generator>
        
            <item>
                <title>Kodaikanal</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;It was the 28th of April, and we were sitting in the office, realizing that most of us had no plans for the upcoming long weekend—thanks to Labour Day falling on the 1st of May. The work mood was already dead, and everyone was half in vacation mode.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s when we randomly decided: “Let’s go to Kodaikanal!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The plan started with five of us—me, Aditya, Vinay, Abhay, and Nithin. We quickly split the tasks: I began looking for car rental options, while Abhay and Aditya took charge of finding a place to stay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But clearly, we weren’t the only ones with this brilliant last-minute idea. Almost every Airbnb in Kodaikanal was either booked or absurdly overpriced. The car situation was worse—only 1–2 cars were available, that too at ridiculous rates. Luckily, I managed to pull a favor and arranged a car from a friend who rents vehicles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As expected during long weekends, no one in the office was actually working. People were buzzing about their own plans—some heading to Coorg, others to Ooty. The bottom line? No one was staying back in Bangalore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, we managed to find a decent Airbnb in Kodaikanal. But just after we booked it, we got a call from the host saying the property “wasn’t available anymore.” He offered us another one that “belonged to a friend,” which was more expensive and clearly inferior in quality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve dealt with this Airbnb trick before—hosts use attractive photos to lure customers, only to redirect them to different properties (usually outside the app) to avoid platform commissions and increase rates. After some back-and-forth, we politely declined and started the search again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, with just one day left, we had only the car figured out—and nothing else. That’s when another issue popped up: I realized I’d be the only one driving. Kodaikanal is around 460 km from Bangalore—roughly a 9-hour drive. I could manage the distance, but not with four non-drivers in the car. I’d be too exhausted to enjoy the views or explore once we got there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, we ditched the car idea and started looking into trains and buses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bus prices were insanely high, and trains were fully booked. Our last shot: Tatkal booking. We crossed our fingers and, to our surprise, managed to grab confirmed tickets. We were finally set!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s when Nithin had to back out due to health reasons. So now it was just four of us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually, we found another Airbnb—this one right in front of the Kodaikanal lake. It looked nice, was reasonably priced, and more importantly, available. We locked it in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our train was scheduled to depart around 7 PM, so we planned to leave office by 4 PM, head home, pack, and reach SMVT Railway Station by 6:30.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just as we were about to leave, I received an SMS—the train was delayed by 4 hours. So we dumped our bags back in the office and resumed our legendary bakchodi session.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By 8 PM, we finally decided to head out. Since all of us lived within a 2–3 km radius, the plan was to pick everyone up on the way to the station.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aditya booked a cab. He first picked up Abhay, then Vinay, and was on his way to get me when the cab driver got super annoyed about the multiple stops. He demanded extra money. We firmly told him, “Bhai, we’ve paid what the app says. That’s it.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He got pissed and dropped everyone at Vinay’s place—and left.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, the three of them were stuck at Vinay’s, and I was waiting at my place with my bag packed. To make things worse, it had started drizzling. Auto drivers were refusing to go to the station, which was expected—SMVT is crowded and chaotic in the evenings, and it was peak hour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After an hour of trying, I finally got an auto—but only after agreeing to pay ₹600 for a ride that usually costs ₹150–200. Same was the case for the others. Everyone ended up shelling out 500–600 bucks just to reach the station.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We all eventually made it, only to find out that the train was delayed by another hour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After another hour of waiting, we boarded the train and settled into our seats. Thankfully, all four of us were in the same compartment. We were excited and started chatting and joking around. But the coach was full, and soon an uncle gave us the classic “keep it down, boys” speech. We lowered the volume and, soon after, everyone crashed for the night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Day 1 – Reaching Kodai
We woke up around 6 AM. Our plan was to get off at Madurai, have breakfast there, and then figure out our route to Kodaikanal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the way, the train stopped at Kodaikanal Road station. We were like, “Wait—isn’t this the stop for Kodai?” Technically, it is. Kodaikanal Road is about 80 km from the hill town. From there, you can hire a cab or take a bus uphill. But since we weren’t sure about the availability of transport from there and didn’t want to risk being stranded, we stuck to our original plan: get down at Madurai.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We reached Madurai around 9 AM. The moment we stepped out of the train, the heat hit us like a truck. Coming from Bangalore’s chill weather, we were sweating within minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We asked around and were told to head to the bus stand to catch a bus to Kodaikanal. The bus stand was about 1 km from the railway station, so we hopped into an auto and got there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;gallery-box&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;gallery&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/internal/kodaikanal/IMG20250430232533.jpg&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/internal/kodaikanal/IMG_20250501_093102114.jpg&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Photos of SMVT railway staion at night and bus stand of madurai&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After reaching Madurai bus stand, we asked around for the next bus to Kodaikanal—only to be told that the last one had left just 10 minutes ago. The next bus was scheduled in about an hour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That worked out perfectly—we were starving anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right across from the bus stand, we found a decent enough pure veg restaurant. Nothing fancy, but it did the job. We grabbed a quick breakfast, rehydrated ourselves after the train ride and the heat, and made our way back to the bus stand just in time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We boarded the bus to Kodaikanal—a 3-hour uphill journey through winding mountain roads. Naturally, we took the last row so all four of us could sit together and continue the nonsense we’d been spouting since the night before. The ride was bumpy, to say the least. At one point, we all looked at each other and said, “Thank god Nithin didn’t come—his back would’ve never survived this!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of us dozed off midway, while others kept gazing out at the changing landscape. As the bus ascended, the air grew cooler, the views greener, and our excitement louder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, we arrived in Kodaikanal! The moment we stepped out, we felt the chill in the air—it was bliss. After the Madurai heat, the refreshing mountain breeze hit differently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, almost all of us stepped out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just as I was about to get off, the bus suddenly started moving. I didn’t dare make a risky jump, so I had no choice but to go to the next stop. It wasn’t too far—about half a kilometer—so I hopped off there and walked back to reunite with the others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that we were officially in Kodai, it was time to plan our sightseeing. We spoke to a few cab drivers standing near the bus stand, got an idea of the common tourist spots, and took down a few phone numbers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We told one cabbie to stay on standby—we’d start our sightseeing by 5 PM. It was around 2 PM at that point, so we had some time to kill.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luckily, we were standing right next to the famous Kodaikanal Lake. Our Airbnb was just a 10-minute walk away, along the lakeside road. But first—snacks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We spotted some local vendors selling roasted corn, raw mango slices with chili-salt mix, and freshly cut pineapple. One bite into that pineapple and we were sold. It was incredibly sweet and juicy—unlike any we’d had before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We didn’t stop at one. Or two. Between the four of us, we must have polished off at least 5–10 pineapples. We just kept buying more. The vendor was amused, and probably grateful too. Honestly, that pineapple deserves a Michelin star.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After about half an hour of feasting on nature’s candy, we decided to finally check into our Airbnb.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We called the property manager, who was already waiting for us. He handed over the keys and showed us around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The property didn’t disappoint—two clean, cozy rooms perfect for the four of us, a nice sitting area, and a great location just off the lake. We were more than satisfied. After the chaos of the last 48 hours, it finally felt like vacation mode had officially begun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;gallery-box&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;gallery&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/internal/kodaikanal/IMG-20250501-WA0010.jpg&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/internal/kodaikanal/IMG20250501155736.jpg&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Photos of locations to visit in kodaikanal and just outside of out airbnb&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After settling into our Airbnb and freshening up, we headed out to explore Kodaikanal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our cab driver arrived—and here comes a story worth telling. The man was a gem. A cheerful Christian fellow who told us how he gave up drinking after “coming under the light of God.” His energy was infectious, and we knew this trip was going to be special with him around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our first destination was Vattakanal Waterfalls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The moment we reached, we were greeted by the sound of rushing water and the cool mist of the falls. The stream was freezing—we didn’t get fully into the water, but even dipping our feet gave us chills (the good kind). We spent some time clicking photos and shooting videos, soaking in the view—both literally and figuratively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, we set out for the Dolphin’s Nose Viewpoint. The trail involved a short but slightly steep downhill hike. However, by the time we got there, it was already past 5 PM, and the entry was closed. Bit of a bummer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But not for long—we noticed another nearby viewpoint just a short walk away. The view was almost the same—misty mountains, deep valleys, and layers of clouds rolling over the hills. We started with solo photo sessions (naturally), and then decided to get a group photo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We asked a bystander for help, and just as we posed, we heard a laugh that sounded too familiar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We turned around—and lo and behold—it was a colleague from our office! She was also vacationing in Kodaikanal, completely unaware that we were there too. It was such a fun, random moment. She photobombed our group photo perfectly, joined us for a quick picture, and then went on her way. Small world, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After that little surprise, we made our way to Altaf Café.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a small, cozy spot perched on the edge of the hills, offering a mist-covered view of the valley below. The place had a relaxed vibe, perfect for unwinding. We ordered some light snacks and tea, and just sat there—chatting, laughing, and enjoying the cool weather and scenic views. It was the kind of moment you want to hit pause on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Food, Fog &amp;amp; a Birthday Twist
As dusk turned to night, we headed back to our Airbnb to freshen up and relax for a bit. For dinner, we decided to try Hilltop Woodlands Inn, a pure vegetarian restaurant nearby.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The place had a clean, homely ambiance and served pretty good North Indian food—which, after all the travel, tasted amazing. Rich curries, hot rotis, and that comforting spice hit the spot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But no meal is truly complete without dessert, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We found a small ice cream parlour nearby and decided to treat ourselves. They had a surprisingly good variety for such a tiny outlet, and as we were sampling different flavors, someone suddenly remembered—“Wait, wasn’t it Vinay’s birthday a few days back?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And just like that, it turned into a mini celebration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We ordered an ice cream cake, sang a very uncoordinated birthday song for him, and dug in. It was simple, spontaneous, and super sweet—literally and emotionally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With happy bellies and happier hearts, we walked back to our Airbnb, laughing about everything that had happened that day—from near-missed waterfalls to surprise office reunions to birthday ice cream.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We finally crashed into our beds, tired but content. Day one in Kodai was a wrap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gallery-box&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;gallery&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/internal/kodaikanal/IMG_20250501_163140488.jpg&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/internal/kodaikanal/IMG20250501160206.jpg&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/internal/kodaikanal/IMG-20250501-WA0016.jpg&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/internal/kodaikanal/IMG20250501180022.jpg&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/internal/kodaikanal/IMG20250501202556.jpg&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Photos of Vattakanal Waterfalls, we all in the cab , the mountain viewpoint, and view from Altaf Cafe, we all celebrating vinay&apos;s bday&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Day two in Kodaikanal started very early. Our mission? Book Tatkal train tickets for the return journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, booking Tatkal tickets with slow internet is like running a 100m sprint with one leg tied. So we roped in some friends from Bangalore and Gurgaon to help with the booking process. Ironically, our plan worked a little too well—both me and my friend managed to book the tickets successfully, and we ended up overbooking. Classic us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the time all that chaos settled, it was already 10 AM, and we were still in bed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We freshened up and skipped a proper breakfast—just munched on a couple of energy bars. Our cab driver (the same cheerful man from day one) was running quite late that morning, so we took the opportunity to sit by the lake, soak in the peaceful vibes, and enjoy the crisp morning air. It was calm, quiet, and a perfect start to the day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the cab arrived, we started our sightseeing for the day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our first stop was the Kodaikanal Golf Course—a lush green stretch that looked straight out of a postcard. Even if you’re not into golf, it’s a beautiful place to walk around, take in the views, and of course, click some nice photos. We did all three.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, we drove to Suicide Point—officially renamed Green Valley View (but let’s be honest, no one calls it that). Unfortunately, the viewpoint was completely covered in clouds, so visibility was pretty low, but the misty air added a kind of dreamy touch to the surroundings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From there, we moved on to Pillar Rocks and the Pillar Rock Flower Garden.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These massive vertical rock formations were wrapped in clouds—it looked absolutely surreal. One moment the rocks would be hidden, and the next, the clouds would clear just enough to reveal the towering cliffs. It was one of those sights you just stand and admire. We spent a good amount of time here clicking photos, especially with the flowers around the garden adding a burst of color.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then came the Pine Forest Road, one of the more iconic and Instagram-worthy spots in Kodaikanal. Tall pine trees lined up neatly on either side of the path, with soft needles carpeting the ground—it felt straight out of a movie set.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our final stop for the day was Guna Cave, made famous by the Kamal Haasan movie Guna. We were excited to see it—until we arrived.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It felt like half of Bangalore had shown up there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The place was absolutely packed. We could barely move, let alone enjoy the scenery or take photos. Within minutes, we knew it wasn’t worth the struggle. We took a quick look at the cave area from afar, snapped a couple of hurried pictures, and decided to leave before we got completely swallowed by the crowd.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a bit of a letdown, but hey—not every spot can be a win during a long weekend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;gallery-box&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;gallery&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/internal/kodaikanal/IMG20250502105922.jpg&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/internal/kodaikanal/IMG20250502105745.jpg&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/internal/kodaikanal/IMG20250502124603.jpg&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/internal/kodaikanal/IMG_20250502_130043846.jpg&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/internal/kodaikanal/IMG20250502141942.jpg&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/internal/kodaikanal/IMG_20250502_132507344.jpg&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Photos of adity waiting for the cab, we leavoing our messy room, suicide point, us at the golf course, crowded Guna Cave, and pillar rock flower garden&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After finishing up at Guna Cave, we decided to explore the rural side of Kodaikanal, especially the step farming areas near Poomparai village. It was going to be a long ride through winding mountain roads, and by then we were super hungry—we hadn’t had a proper breakfast or lunch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We asked our cab driver to stop at any pure veg restaurant on the way. He pulled into a decent-looking place called Woody’s Cafeteria. It had glass walls, a clean interior, and seemed nice at first glance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We ordered Italian food—pizza and pasta—and asked our driver to join us for lunch too, telling him to order whatever he liked. His food came out first—typical South Indian dishes—while we were still waiting for ours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What happened next completely killed the vibe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Turns out, Woody’s had a weird policy: they had separate seating areas for Indian and Italian food, and you couldn’t bring Indian food into the Italian section. A waiter came over and rudely told our cab driver he wasn’t allowed to sit there with his food.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Naturally, our driver got upset and tried to reason with them. But things escalated fast. Harsh words were exchanged between the restaurant staff, the owner, and our cab driver. Realizing the scene was heating up, we tried to defuse the situation. We told the staff to just parcel our food, and we’d eat it in the cab.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But no—since we had already prepaid, the owner refused to cancel or parcel the order. And the shouting only got louder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point, we’d had enough. We tried to calm our cab driver down and convinced him to leave. As we drove off, he asked, “Did you at least get your refund?” We didn’t want to trigger him again, so we said yes—even though we hadn’t. But he immediately saw through our lie, turned the vehicle around, and parked it right in the middle of the narrow mountain road, blocking traffic in both directions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Suddenly, we were causing a full-on traffic jam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other taxi drivers and bus drivers got out of their vehicles, yelling in Tamil. But once our cabbie explained the situation, they rallied behind him. One of them even dragged the restaurant owner by the collar out to the street. The crowd was this close to beating him up—but we stepped in just in time to stop it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We politely told the restaurant owner, “Let’s not escalate this further. Just give us our food, and we’ll leave peacefully.” Still, he refused.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soon, the police arrived. They questioned both the owner and our cab driver. After a lot of shouting, back-and-forth drama, and a full-on mountain road traffic crisis… we left without our food.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our cab driver, still fuming, vowed to make sure the restaurant never gets business again—especially from the Kodaikanal taxi union. He felt guilty that we were hungry and that the whole incident ruined part of our trip. So, in true local-hero fashion, he took us on a mini food tour of his friends’ places.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One had great hot soup, another served crispy dosas, and each stop made up for the unpleasantness at Woody’s. We probably made 3-4 stops, grabbing small bites and chatting with friendly locals. We even stopped at the local police station to officially file a complaint against the restaurant—because, well, justice matters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, the Calm: Poomparai Village &amp;amp; Owl Hollow Stays
Eventually, we reached Poomparai Village, a small and peaceful town surrounded by lush green hills and terraced step farms. The weather was pleasant, the air was clean, and we finally felt like we could breathe again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We walked around, soaking in the views and clicking some photos. The landscape was incredibly beautiful, and the village had a serene, almost meditative vibe. If you’re ever in Kodaikanal and want a quiet weekend escape, this is the place to be. There were a few camping sites here too—perfect for a night under the stars.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On our way back, we stopped at a lovely wooden homestay called Owl Hollow Stays. Built in a rustic style with wood interiors and large windows, it offered an amazing view of the surrounding valley. We didn’t stay there, but it’s definitely going on our list for the next trip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;gallery-box&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;gallery&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/internal/kodaikanal/IMG20250502152327.jpg&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/internal/kodaikanal/IMG20250502165456.jpg&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/internal/kodaikanal/IMG20250502182234.jpg&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Photos of valley view from some randome viewpoint, poomparai village, and owl hollow stays&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the chaos at Woody’s and a long, emotionally charged day, we were exhausted by the time we returned to Kodaikanal. It was around 8 PM when we reached back, and the first thing on our minds was food.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We asked our cab driver to drop us at Hotel Astoria Veg, a place I had noticed earlier and remembered for its great reviews online. It looked promising from the outside—but the moment we stepped in, things started going downhill again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, we had to wait over 30 minutes just to get a table. The place was jam-packed, clearly short-staffed, and once seated, it took another 30 minutes before anyone even came to take our order. The waiter who finally did was rude, impatient, and made the whole experience feel worse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We ordered a few light dishes, but unfortunately, the food was pretty underwhelming. At that point, though, we were so hungry that we didn’t care—we just ate what we could and called it a night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Day 3: Work, Wander &amp;amp; The Calm After the Storm&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We woke up early the next day, but it wasn’t exactly a vacation morning. There was a production issue at work, so Aditya and Vinay had to get on their laptops and troubleshoot. That meant a slow start to the day, and we decided to just stay in the Airbnb for the time being.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a while, boredom kicked in, so Abhay and I decided to step out and explore a bit. We walked around the lake area, and stumbled upon a 7D theater nearby. It sounded fun, so we bought tickets and watched a 15-minute 7D movie—full of effects, motion, wind, and sound. It was short but actually quite fun and refreshing!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soon, Vinay wrapped up his work and joined us. The three of us headed to the boathouse, rented a pedal boat, and spent some peaceful time boating on the lake. Surrounded by hills, mist, and calm waters, it was just what we needed after the chaos of the previous day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The whole experience was relaxing and therapeutic, giving us a chance to just breathe, laugh, and soak in the beauty of Kodaikanal Lake—one of those simple moments that quietly become your favorite part of the trip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;gallery-box&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;gallery&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/internal/kodaikanal/IMG20250503135851.jpg&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/internal/kodaikanal/IMG_20250503_143956828.jpg&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Photos of me and abhay at 7D theatre, we 3 boating&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even on our last day, we still didn’t have a ride confirmed to get back to Kodai Road Railway Station. This time, we decided on Kodai Road instead of Dindigul, since it was closer and more convenient.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, we packed up and walked around to find a cab that could take us to the station. After some searching, we finally found a cab and started our journey back down the hills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our driver turned out to be a really nice and humble guy. We had a heartfelt conversation with him about his son’s education, future career paths, and how he wanted his son to study hard and not follow in his footsteps as a cab driver. It was one of those unexpectedly genuine conversations that stay with you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the way, we stopped at a small pure veg restaurant for lunch—and to our surprise, we ran into Sunny from our PV team, who was there with his family. Even more of a coincidence: we were on the same train back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we reached the railway station, the cab fare was ₹2200, and we decided to give him a ₹300 tip, rounding it off to ₹2500. But by mistake, Abhay transferred ₹2800 instead. We all just laughed and said, “Well, guess he deserves a ₹600 tip!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the station, we met up with Sunny again, and also got to say hi to his adorable son. While we waited for our train, we were sitting at the entrance of the station, just chilling and chatting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But right before boarding, as we moved to Platform 2, Abhay suddenly realized he had left his bag back on Platform 1. He and Vinay sprinted back to retrieve it while Aditya and I stayed put. Thankfully, they got it just in time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We boarded our train, found our seats, and were relieved to see that all four of us were seated together. Sunny had an RAC ticket, so technically he had only one confirmed berth, but we invited him to hang out with us anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We played UNO and regular card games for hours, laughing and chatting late into the night. Of course, Aditya still had OpsGenie calls even on the train—classic!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At some point, an uncle nearby complained that we were too loud and that the lights were disturbing him. So we quieted down, and ingeniously hooked a blanket at the end of our compartment to block the light. Surprisingly, it worked perfectly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Goodbye, Kodai
By the time we called it a night, it was already early morning. Around 4 AM, we deboarded at Karmelaram Station, took an auto back home, and finally brought our journey to a close.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a fun, chaotic, heartfelt trip filled with unexpected moments, great conversations, some drama, and lots of laughter. We were glad we went, explored a new place, made some memories—and had one more travel story to tell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;gallery-box&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;gallery&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/internal/kodaikanal/IMG20250503224632.jpg&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/internal/kodaikanal/IMG20250503213208.jpg&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/internal/kodaikanal/IMG_20250503_200032411.jpg&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;image&quot; /&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Photos of us playing uno after blocking the light using a blanket, aditya taking opsgenie call, kodaiknal road railway station&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 22:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
                <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/kodaikanal</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/kodaikanal</guid>
                
                <category>_2025_</category>
                
                <category>bangalore</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Hampi</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Exploring Hampi: A Journey of Adventure, Laughter, and Unexpected Surprises&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It had been a while since my last trip outside Bangalore, and with a long weekend approaching, the urge to escape was strong. My friend Mohit and I decided to take a short trip, and after checking with our other college friends (who unfortunately were busy), it was just the three of us—Mohit, his girlfriend Juhi, and me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Journey Begins: A Chaotic Start&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To make the most of our time, we booked an overnight bus from Bangalore to Hampi. The plan was simple: meet up for dinner at HSR Layout, board the bus by 9:00 PM, and wake up in Hospet, the nearest city to Hampi, by 4:00 AM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything was going smoothly until Mohit called me in a panic while I was on my way to deliver a Zoomcar vehicle. We had miscalculated the departure time—the bus was leaving at 9:00 PM, not 10:00 PM! Mohit and Juhi managed to board the bus at Madiwala, but I had to think fast. With just 45 minutes before the bus would reach Anand Rao Circle, I knew a cab wouldn’t cut it in Bangalore’s traffic. I quickly booked a Rapido bike, and thanks to a speedy driver who weaved through the traffic like a pro, I reached the pickup point just in time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The adventure had begun even before we left Bangalore!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Suspicious Encounter at the Bus Station&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Knowing there wouldn’t be any dinner breaks, I decided to use a pay-and-use washroom at the station. As I handed over ₹10 to the attendant, something felt off. Typically, such facilities charge ₹3-₹5. I checked the board outside, but the pricing details were suspiciously covered with paint or stickers. As I kept looking, the attendant got nervous and suddenly called me back, returning ₹5. While I didn’t argue further, it was clear he had been overcharging people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With this little victory, I boarded the bus, settled into my seat, and got comfortable for the journey ahead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reaching Hospet: The Auto Fare Hustle&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bus ride was smooth, and by 4:00 AM, we arrived in Hospet, where we were immediately swarmed by auto drivers. Their initial quotes were ridiculous—₹1000 for a short trip to Hampi, or ₹3500 for a full-day tour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We tried negotiating with a nearby group of four travelers, but they weren’t interested in sharing. One girl rudely dismissed us, saying they had a pre-booked cab. Not letting this dampen our spirits, we finally bargained an auto for ₹500 and reached Hampi in 40 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Matunga Hill: A Breathtaking Sunrise&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our first stop was a small tea stall, where we warmed up with chai in the chilly morning air. The auto driver suggested visiting Malyavanta Hill for sunrise, but after checking Google reviews, we chose Matunga Hill instead—it was closer and had better views.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the base, we met three other travelers, and together, we started our 20-minute hike in total darkness. It was surreal, trying to spot Hampi’s temples just by their silhouettes. Once at the top, we removed our shoes at a small temple and settled in, waiting for the sunrise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The peaceful moment didn’t last long. A chai vendor warned us about the monkeys that would soon arrive looking for food. Right on cue, a troop of them appeared, scanning for unattended bags. One sneaky monkey sat next to my bag, unzipped it, and pulled out my UNO cards! What followed was a chaotic battle of wits, with the monkey determined to escape with its newfound treasure. It even pulled out my toothbrush and shampoo before I managed to snatch the bag back—but not before it ran off with my UNO deck. Everyone burst into laughter at the absurdity of the situation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the sun finally rose, casting golden light over the ancient ruins, we clicked some stunning pictures and soaked in the beauty of Hampi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gallery-box&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;gallery&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/internal/hampi_blog/vlcsnap-2025-03-24-08h59m02s809.png&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;Video Snap 3&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/internal/hampi_blog/vlcsnap-2025-03-24-09h01m55s073.png&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;Video Snap 4&quot; /&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/internal/hampi_blog/IMG_9262.jpg&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;Hampi Image 7&quot; /&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Photos of Matanga hills&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hampi Bazaar and Stone Chariot Temple&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Descending the hill, we got our first proper look at Hampi in daylight. The ancient Hampi Bazaar stretched for half a kilometer, with stone pillars forming what was once a bustling marketplace. Centuries ago, merchants traded everything from diamonds to groceries here—it was fascinating to imagine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We hired an auto for ₹2000 to explore Hampi’s key sites. Our first stop was Vijaya Vittala Temple, home to the famous stone chariot featured on the ₹50 note. On the way, I convinced the auto driver to let me drive, and for 5 km, I took control of the rickshaw, navigating the bumpy roads with glee!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gallery-box&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;gallery&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/internal/hampi_blog/vlcsnap-2025-03-24-09h03m11s287.png&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;Video Snap 5&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/internal/hampi_blog/vlcsnap-2025-03-24-09h05m52s925.png&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;Video Snap 6&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/internal/hampi_blog/DJI_20250315090615_0034_D.JPG&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;Hampi Image 1&quot; /&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Photos of Auto ride&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the temple, we met a Polish traveler who was an avid biker. We bonded over our love for road trips, but since he was heading to Mysore next, our plans didn’t align. After taking the mandatory picture with the stone chariot, we moved on to explore more of Hampi’s royal heritage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;gallery-box&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;gallery&quot;&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/internal/hampi_blog/IMG_9380.jpg&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;Hampi Image 9&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/internal/hampi_blog/IMG_9296.jpg&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;Hampi Image 8&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/internal/hampi_blog/DJI_20250315093040_0045_D.JPG&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;Hampi Image 2&quot; /&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/internal/hampi_blog/IMG_9389.jpg&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;Hampi Image 10&quot; /&gt;

    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Photos of stone chariot&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Dal Disaster and Sunset Serenity&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By midday, exhaustion kicked in, and we stopped at Happy Hampi Café. The restaurant had a unique setup—mattresses on the floor instead of chairs. We lay down, finally getting some rest, when suddenly, chaos struck.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mohit accidentally knocked over a dal container, drenching himself and Juhi in yellow dal. The sight of them, completely covered in dal, had us all in stitches. It took a moment to process what had happened before we burst into uncontrollable laughter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gallery-box&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;gallery&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/internal/hampi_blog/IMG20250315163436.jpg&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;Hampi Image 6&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/internal/hampi_blog/DJI_20250315155550_0077_D.JPG&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;Hampi Image 4&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/internal/hampi_blog/DJI_20250315155707_0079_D.JPG&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;Hampi Image 5&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/internal/hampi_blog/IMG_9475.jpg&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;Hampi Image 11&quot; /&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/internal/hampi_blog/DJI_20250315155331_0074_D.JPG&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;Hampi Image 3&quot; /&gt;

    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Photos of lotus palace&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a good meal and some much-needed downtime, we continued exploring more temples before heading to Tungabhadra Lake for a coracle boat ride.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Initially, we hesitated due to the ₹500 per person charge, but eventually, we went for it. As we paddled across the calm waters, the setting sun cast a golden glow over the landscape. I even got a chance to row the boat, only to realize how physically exhausting it was! Watching the sunset from the middle of the lake, with our hands dipped in the cool water, was the perfect way to end our day in Hampi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gallery-box&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;gallery&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/internal/hampi_blog/vlcsnap-2025-03-24-08h48m26s754.png&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;Video Snap 1&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/internal/hampi_blog/vlcsnap-2025-03-24-08h55m09s518.png&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;Video Snap 2&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Photos of boat ride&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wrapping Up: Shopping and the Journey Back&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We stopped at the Hampi market to buy some fridge magnets as souvenirs before heading back to Hospet. Since our bus was at 9:00 PM, we had plenty of time for a leisurely dinner. We tried a nearby ice cream parlor with an overwhelming number of flavor combinations before finally boarding our bus back to Bangalore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By 4:00 AM, we were back in the city, exhausted but happy. Mohit booked a cab, and just like that, our whirlwind trip to Hampi came to an end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Final Thoughts&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From unexpected bus chases to monkey heists and dal disasters, this trip had everything—adventure, history, and laughter. Hampi, with its ancient ruins and surreal landscapes, had given us memories to cherish forever. Until the next adventure!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
                <pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2025 10:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
                <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/hampi</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/hampi</guid>
                
                <category>_2025_</category>
                
                <category>bangalore</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Shri Adinatha Digambara Jaina Basadi (Anivalu)</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;A Day of Volunteering: Restoring a Forgotten Jain Temple
I’m part of a Gyanoday Bachelors group on WhatsApp. It’s a great community in Bangalore that serves multiple purposes—finding Jain flatmates (mostly around the Gyanoday temple), sharing airport rides, organizing travel through the “Wanderers” subgroup, volunteering at temples, and generally helping young people stay connected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of the group members live around the Gyanoday temple. Since the group is always buzzing with messages, I usually check in once a week, skimming through the 200–300 unread messages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One day, an image caught my attention—it was a photo of a temple, but the entire poster was in Kannada, so I couldn’t understand it. Below the image was a caption that read, “Final reminder.” It linked to an older message in the group. I followed the link and found a detailed post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was about restoring an old Jain temple, which had become overgrown and forgotten due to lack of maintenance and absence of a Jain community in that town. The temple was in Anivalu, about 300 km from Bangalore. The organizers had arranged transport from Bangalore, and food was sponsored—but each participant would need to cover their own travel cost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It sounded like a great cause. I didn’t have any plans for the weekend anyway, so I messaged the admin for more details. He replied promptly and shared the full itinerary. The plan was to leave from Karnataka Jain Association at 6 AM, reach Anivalu in about four hours, clean the temple for three hours, visit a few nearby temples, and return to Bangalore by sunset.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I asked if there was a seat available and confirmed my spot. I also checked if there was bike parking at the starting point since getting an auto at 4:30 AM would be difficult. Once all was sorted, I slept early to prepare for the next day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Next Morning
I woke up at 4:30 AM. Karnataka Jain Association was about 15 km from my place, so I quickly got ready and left around 5 AM. It was still dark outside, and I had never been to this part of Bangalore before. But it felt nice—cool early morning breeze, empty roads, and I was humming some tunes while cruising.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I reached, I saw around 20 people gathered at the entrance—mostly under 25, standing in small circles. I parked my bike and joined them. I had assumed that most people would be from Bundelkhand since the Gyanoday community has a strong presence from that region. But to my surprise, no one was from Bundelkhand. I tried to strike up a few conversations, but the language barrier kicked in—most were speaking Kannada.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went inside the temple for darshan, but at the back of my mind, I was wondering if I’d made a mistake. I was hoping to meet some new people and have a fun experience, but everyone seemed to already know each other, and the language difference felt like a wall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were still waiting for the bus and for a few more people to join. The initial plan was to carry breakfast and eat en route, but due to delays, the plan changed—we would eat breakfast first and then leave.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyone washed up in the dharamshala next to the temple and lined up for breakfast—idli and bisibelebath. While eating, I noticed a guy who also wasn’t mingling with the others. He seemed older—maybe 5 to 8 years senior to me. I figured he was probably not from Karnataka either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We ended up having breakfast together and started chatting. He was from North India and had spent most of his life abroad. He studied at UC Berkeley and worked outside India for several years before returning. It was refreshing to see someone so humble and community-minded despite his international background.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the Road
After breakfast and tea, we boarded the bus. It was a 50-seater, but only about 35–40 seats were occupied. We left around 7:30 AM. Honestly, I was sure we wouldn’t be back by sunset.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The city roads were bumpy, so I waited for us to hit the highway before trying to nap. I dozed off for 1–2 hours until we took a break. Some folks who missed breakfast ate, while others stretched their legs. I stayed near the bus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nearby, a group of guys in their early 20s were joking around. One of them asked if I was with someone, and I replied, “Nope, I came alone.” We started talking. Turned out they were regulars from the Gyanoday Abhishek group and visited the temple daily. Two were from Karnataka, two from the North. One guy, Akkole ji, was from Sadalga, the hometown of our guru Acharya Shri Ji.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While others finished eating, we crossed the road for tea. Watching biker groups zoom past on the Mangalore highway reminded me of my own bike trips.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back on the bus, I sat with these new friends. One of them, also named Paras Jain, worked at Netradyne and had studied at IIT BHU. Every year, they organize a sponsored Shikharji trip for around 150 Jain juniors from his college. We even chatted a bit about work—coding, database optimization, and the usual tech stuff. Time flew, and we reached Anivalu around 12:30 PM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;gallery-box&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;gallery&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/internal/anivalu/DSC_0085.JPG&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;Anivalu Image 1&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/internal/anivalu/IMG20250216132323.jpg&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;Anivalu Image 2&quot; /&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/internal/anivalu/DSC_0218.JPG&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;Anivalu Image 3&quot; /&gt;
            &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/internal/anivalu/DSC_0141.JPG&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;Anivalu Image 2&quot; /&gt;

        &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;em&gt;Photos of Temple before cleaing&lt;/em&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Restoration Begins
The local Jain community welcomed us warmly. We washed our hands and climbed about 30 steps to the temple. At first glance, it was clear the temple hadn’t been maintained in years—bushes everywhere, layers of dust.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;gallery-box&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;gallery&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/internal/anivalu/DSC_0149.JPG&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;Anivalu Image 3&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/internal/anivalu/DSC_0161.JPG&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;Anivalu Image 4&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/internal/anivalu/DSC_0171.JPG&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;Anivalu Image 5&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/internal/anivalu/DSC_0295.JPG&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;Anivalu Image 7&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/internal/anivalu/DSC_0412.JPG&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;Anivalu Image 9&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/internal/anivalu/DSC_0708.JPG&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;Anivalu Image 13&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/internal/anivalu/IMG-20250216-WA0049.jpg&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;Anivalu Image 17&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Photos of Temple during cleaning&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coincidentally, the temple got its electricity connection that very day. After the meter was inaugurated, we did darshan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We unloaded our cleaning tools—axes, sickles, shears, brooms, shovels, rakes, wheelbarrows, buckets, trash bags, pickaxes, and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People split into teams—some started cleaning the inside, and I joined the group working outside.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though untrained, we went all in—cutting grass, clearing thorns, removing trash. I was sweating like crazy, but it felt good doing something for the community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some removed huge thorny bushes; others cleared years of dust from the ground. A few climbed up to clean the temple roof.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After an hour or so, we could finally see the stone floor around the temple—about 2 meters wide for parikrama. It was satisfying to uncover it after all the cleaning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We paused for snacks—buttermilk, water, and some namkeen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inside, a small group was scrubbing floors and walls with soap and water. Later, someone arranged a petrol-powered grass cutter, which sped up the work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We gathered all the trash and started burning it. I sat with my new friends again and we chatted about random things. Some elderly people were sitting nearby too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One old lady came up and thanked us. Then she said something in Kannada I couldn’t understand. My friends translated—she wanted some utensils. I handed them over. When they told her I was from the North and didn’t know Kannada, her expression changed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She frowned, visibly disappointed. She told us we should learn Kannada if we’re living in Karnataka. Another uncle joined in and echoed the same. I smiled and nodded, saying, “Yes uncle, I’ll learn.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But in my head, I was thinking, I’m not even staying here long-term… and even if I were, why is learning Kannada a requirement?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That interaction left a bitter taste. It didn’t matter that I came from afar and was helping restore their temple—they were more bothered about the language I spoke. For a second, I wondered if it was even worth it. But I shook off those thoughts and reminded myself to stay in the moment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;gallery-box&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;gallery&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/internal/anivalu/DSC_0618.JPG&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;Anivalu Image 12&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/internal/anivalu/DSC_0777.JPG&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;Anivalu Image 15&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/internal/anivalu/DSC_0391.JPG&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;Anivalu Image 8&quot; /&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/internal/anivalu/IMG-20250216-WA0064.jpg&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;Anivalu Image 18&quot; /&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Photos of Temple after cleaing&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Job Well Done
After three hours of hard work, the temple looked beautiful. Cleaned inside and out, with all the bushes gone, it felt like we had brought something back to life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We took some group pictures and then had lunch—bisibelebath, curd, chips, and pickle. Maybe the food was genuinely delicious, or maybe we were just famished from the effort. Either way, it hit the spot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We went inside for darshan and pooja. The temple looked divine. The pooja was led by the local priest, and afterward, the community members gave a heartfelt thank-you speech.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;gallery-box&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;gallery&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/internal/anivalu/DSC_0603.JPG&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;Anivalu Image 11&quot; /&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/internal/anivalu/DSC_0761.JPG&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;Anivalu Image 14&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/internal/anivalu/DSC_0785.JPG&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;Anivalu Image 16&quot; /&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/internal/anivalu/IMG20250216163239.jpg&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;Anivalu Image 20&quot; /&gt;

        &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;em&gt;Photos of Temple after cleaing&lt;/em&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 
By now it was 5 PM, and we headed to our next stop—a Jain temple in Chikka Hanasoge, about 30 minutes away. From there, we visited several more temples in Saligrama.
Saligrama, we were invited to the home of the family that sponsored our food. They welcomed us warmly and served tea and snacks. We spent some time chatting before heading back to Bangalore around 8 PM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reflections
It was a good day. I made some new friends, had meaningful conversations, and contributed to something worthwhile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once we returned to Bangalore, everyone grabbed their bikes and headed home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite the language gaps and awkward moments, I left with a sense of purpose—and a deeper connection to my community.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2025 10:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
                <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/anivalu-jain-basadi</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/anivalu-jain-basadi</guid>
                
                <category>_2025_</category>
                
                <category>bangalore</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>New Flat Relocation</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Finding a Flat in Bangalore: My Journey from Koramangala to Bellandur
In March 2024, I made a big move in my career—I joined PhonePe, with their office located in Bellandur. At that time, I was living in Koramangala, and although the commute wasn’t too bad initially—roughly 25–35 minutes—I wasn’t in a hurry to relocate. The flat was decent, and the rent was affordable. We were four people sharing the place, each paying around ₹13,000 per month, which later increased to ₹15,000 when the contract was renewed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having lived there since May 2023, I had already settled in. I had sorted out the cook, maid, and my routine. So despite the growing traffic, I kept putting off the thought of moving. But over time, the travel time started stretching. Some days, it took an hour just one way, especially in the late morning heat. On top of that, with my flatmates frequently traveling to their hometowns, my share of the expenses kept increasing. That’s when I finally decided it was time to look for a new place closer to work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gallery-box&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;gallery&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/internal/new_flat_rohan_iksha/old_flat_team_royal/IMG20250101135021.jpg&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;old flat A2&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/internal/new_flat_rohan_iksha/old_flat_team_royal/IMG20250101135100.jpg&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;old flat A3&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/internal/new_flat_rohan_iksha/old_flat_team_royal/IMG20250101135114.jpg&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;old flat A4&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/internal/new_flat_rohan_iksha/old_flat_team_royal/IMG20250101135003.jpg&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;old flat A1&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/internal/new_flat_rohan_iksha/old_flat_team_royal/IMG20250101135223.jpg&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;old flat A8&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/internal/new_flat_rohan_iksha/old_flat_team_royal/IMG20250101135125.jpg&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;old flat A5&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/internal/new_flat_rohan_iksha/old_flat_team_royal/IMG20250101135137.jpg&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;old flat A6&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/internal/new_flat_rohan_iksha/old_flat_team_royal/IMG20250101135152.jpg&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;old flat A7&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/internal/new_flat_rohan_iksha/old_flat_team_royal/IMG20250101135229.jpg&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;old flat A9&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Old flat Team Royal Apartment koramangla&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Flat Hunt Begins: June 2024
I started exploring flats in and around Bellandur, but I quickly realized that most of the options were either too expensive or poorly maintained. After living in apartments for a few years, I wanted to upgrade—somewhere with proper amenities, a gated society, and ideally close to the office.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Around the same time, my friend Mohit told me about a vacancy in his society, Rohan Iksha. It was a well-maintained society with all the amenities I was looking for. But it was around 4 km from my office—only a slight improvement from my current 5.7 km commute. Given the higher rent, I wasn’t sure it was worth the move and decided to continue searching.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually, I lost the motivation to keep looking. But the daily commute kept nagging at me. Some days the traffic was brutal, and I would be stuck in it for hours. Then came a major setback—in late June, I injured my knee badly, which meant surgery and a three-month recovery. The flat hunt came to a complete halt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting Back on Track: October 2024
By October, I had recovered and was still in Koramangala, dealing with the same long commutes. Determined to finally move, I started looking again—NoBroker, 99acres, MagicBricks, Flat &amp;amp; Flatmates on Facebook—I tried everything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My criteria were clear:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Location: Bellandur, Green Glen Layout, or nearby&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pure vegetarian flatmates&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A gated community with amenities&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Within budget&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite visiting 10–20 good societies over two months, each one failed to meet some requirement or the other. Then I met two guys through Facebook—one worked at Uber and preferred Sarjapur Road, and the other was in consulting, so location wasn’t a big issue for him. We teamed up and started hunting for a 3BHK together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But after a couple of weeks, we couldn’t align on a single flat, and eventually, we decided to go our separate ways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Breaking Point: Rent Hike and No Progress
Around the same time, one of my flatmates moved out, and our rent shot up to ₹18,000 per head. My other two flatmates shared their room with friends, so they were paying just ₹9,000 each. Suddenly, my room felt not worth the money, and I knew I had to act fast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, A Breakthrough: December 2024
It was the end of December, and during a casual chat with Mohit, I asked if there were any new vacancies in his society. To my surprise, he said yes! Within five minutes, I had pictures of the flat. I was so exhausted from the months of flat-hunting that I said yes immediately, without even seeing it in person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The pictures looked great, the flat was well-maintained, and I trusted the society. It was a bit on the expensive side, and the room with the attached bathroom was already taken, but I was okay with it. I sent the token amount the same day—my hunt was finally over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gallery-box&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;gallery&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/internal/new_flat_rohan_iksha/IMG-20250101-WA0029.jpg&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;new flat 1&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/internal/new_flat_rohan_iksha/IMG-20250101-WA0030.jpg&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;new flat 2&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/internal/new_flat_rohan_iksha/IMG-20250101-WA0032.jpg&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;new flat 4&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/internal/new_flat_rohan_iksha/IMG-20250101-WA0033.jpg&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;new flat 5&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/internal/new_flat_rohan_iksha/IMG-20250101-WA0034.jpg&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;new flat 6&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/internal/new_flat_rohan_iksha/IMG-20250101-WA0035.jpg&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;new flat 7&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/internal/new_flat_rohan_iksha/IMG-20250101-WA0036.jpg&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;new flat 8&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/internal/new_flat_rohan_iksha/IMG-20250101-WA0037.jpg&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;new flat 9&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/internal/new_flat_rohan_iksha/IMG-20250101-WA0038.jpg&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;new flat 10&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/internal/new_flat_rohan_iksha/IMG-20250101-WA0039.jpg&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;new flat 11&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/internal/new_flat_rohan_iksha/IMG-20250101-WA0040.jpg&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;new flat 12&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Photos of new flat, furniture(though the furniture is not included we had to get our own)&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The New Flat: Rohan Iksha
I moved into the new flat in January 2025. It’s on the 8th floor, with beautiful French windows and a great view. The flat is in excellent condition, and the society has all the amenities I had been hoping for—gym, pool, security, and a good community vibe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The owner is a software engineer, currently living in Bangalore. He bought the flat in 2014 for ₹1 crore, and now it’s valued at around ₹2.5 crores. He’s been responsive and friendly, which is always a plus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking Back
Looking back, the journey was long, tiring, and at times frustrating—but it was all worth it. I’m finally living closer to work, in a peaceful and well-maintained society, with a setup that fits my lifestyle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re planning to move in Bangalore, especially from Koramangala to Bellandur, here’s what I learned:
Start early, don’t wait for things to get worse
Stick to your priorities, but be flexible
Use all platforms—sometimes the best options come from word of mouth
And most importantly, don’t give up
The traffic in Bangalore won’t change overnight—but your living situation can.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2025 10:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
                <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/new-flat</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/new-flat</guid>
                
                <category>_2025_</category>
                
                <category>bangalore</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Nandi Hills</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Our Adventure to Nandi Hills: A Journey of Surprises and Laughter&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It had been a while since Keshav visited Bangalore, and he was about to head back to his hometown. Having recently joined Samsung SDS, where most of the work is remote, staying in Bangalore no longer made sense for him. So, to make the most of his time in the city, we decided to plan a trip. The destination? Nandi Hills. None of us had been there before, and it was about time we checked out this famous spot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The plan was simple: leave early, catch the sunrise, and enjoy a peaceful morning at the hilltop. Our group consisted of Keshav, his brother, Mohit, and myself. The excitement was palpable, even though we had heard mixed reviews about Nandi Hills. People often said it was overrated, with no spectacular views or much to see. But we were determined to make our own experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We decided to take my car for the trip and aimed to leave by 4 AM so that we could reach Nandi Hills by around 5:30 AM. I woke up at 4 AM, full of excitement, even though I had lived in Bangalore for over two years and had never visited Nandi Hills myself. The morning was cool, and the anticipation of the sunrise made the early start worth it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The challenge? Waking up everyone else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keshav and his brother were already up, but Mohit, as usual, was still fast asleep. We tried calling him multiple times, but his phone was on Do Not Disturb mode—something he had forgotten to disable. After numerous unsuccessful attempts to rouse him, we decided to leave without him. It wasn’t the ideal start, but we figured we’d meet him later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By 4:15 AM, we were on the road, with the city still shrouded in darkness. As expected, Bangalore’s notorious traffic was already in full swing. At 4 AM, seriously? I thought we were in the clear, but the Hebbal Flyover had a surprise in store for us. It was slow-moving, and we couldn’t understand why there was so much congestion at that hour. Eventually, we passed the traffic and headed towards Nandi Hills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cool breeze was refreshing as we kept the windows down and cruised through the early morning roads. We started reminiscing about old memories, laughing at inside jokes, and getting to know Keshav’s brother better. It felt like one of those perfect road trips that was more about the journey than the destination.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then came the twist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We took a wrong turn, thinking we were still on the right path. Instead of heading straight to Nandi Hills, we veered off to the right, which led us on a loop around the entire hill. This detour added another 30 minutes to our drive, but eventually, we reached the entrance to Nandi Hills. The sight that greeted us was a little overwhelming: a long line of cars waiting to climb the hill. There were about 200 cars in line, all trying to ascend the winding roads of the hill. And to make matters more interesting, two-wheelers were bypassing us from the right, squeezing through the narrow gaps to avoid the wait. It was a single-lane road, so only one car could go up at a time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hunger set in, and while we were stuck in the long line, Keshav decided to take matters into his own hands. He got out of the slow-moving car and grabbed us some tea and snacks. There we were, sipping tea in the car while waiting in a traffic jam at 5 AM. We joked that we should’ve brought bikes instead of the car—at least we would’ve saved time. The weather, though, was perfect—cold and refreshing. But just as we were getting comfortable, the rain started. We quickly took back our words; the car was definitely the better choice after all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, after another 30 minutes of slow progress, we made it to the top of Nandi Hills. The weather had become even more unpredictable, and the fog was so thick that we could barely see a few meters ahead. The road to the top was steep, and the hairpin bends made it feel like a true hill station drive. But with the fog and rain, we couldn’t see much of the beautiful views that we had hoped for. We honked at every corner, just in case another car was coming from the other side, as the road was so narrow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we reached the top, we parked the car and stepped out into the misty morning. The security guards and police officers were busy directing cars into parking spots, and the whole place had an eerie, quiet vibe. The fog was so dense that we couldn’t see the sunrise at all—just trees and more fog. The anticipation quickly turned to disappointment, but we made the best of it by laughing at the situation. We ate the snacks Keshav had brought and continued talking about random things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It didn’t take long for us to realize that the whole experience was indeed overrated. No sunrise, no sweeping views—just fog, trees, and cold weather. But we weren’t ready to let the trip be a total bust. We decided to take some photos and head back down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the way back, our stomachs were growling. We spotted a few roadside eateries that looked promising, and decided to stop at Adyar Ananda Bhavan (A2B) near Rani Circle. The breakfast was delicious, and it felt good to relax after the adventure. While we were enjoying our food, we struck up a conversation with a group of four men sitting at the table next to ours. They were in their 40s or 50s and seemed to be on a road trip as a reunion. They had started their journey from Nagpur and were on their way to Kanyakumari.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Curious about our travels, they asked for some road trip recommendations. It felt nice to share what we knew and swap travel stories with fellow explorers. It was a reminder that no matter where we go, the journey is as much about the people you meet along the way as it is about the destination.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After breakfast, Keshav took the wheel for the drive back to Bangalore. The mood was light, and we continued to talk about future trips and other places we wanted to explore. The return journey was as fun as the drive to Nandi Hills, and by the time we got back, we were all in good spirits, even if the trip didn’t exactly go as planned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the end, our trip to Nandi Hills might not have been what we expected, but it was a memorable adventure filled with laughs, a little bit of chaos, and plenty of good stories to tell.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2025 06:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
                <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/nandi-hills</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/nandi-hills</guid>
                
                <category>_2025_</category>
                
                <category>bangalore</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Bannerghatta National Park and Benki Falls</title>
                <description>
</description>
                <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 10:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
                <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/bannerghatta-national-park-benki-falls</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/bannerghatta-national-park-benki-falls</guid>
                
                <category>_2025_</category>
                
                <category>bangalore</category>
                
                <category>pending</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Snjana Wedding</title>
                <description>
</description>
                <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 10:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
                <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/sanjana-wedding</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/sanjana-wedding</guid>
                
                <category>_2024_</category>
                
                <category>pending</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Mood Indigo and Zero Latency</title>
                <description>
</description>
                <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 10:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
                <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/mood-indigo-zero-latency</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/mood-indigo-zero-latency</guid>
                
                <category>_2024_</category>
                
                <category>pending</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Sanjana&apos;s Sangeet</title>
                <description>
</description>
                <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 20:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
                <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/sanjana-sangeet</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/sanjana-sangeet</guid>
                
                <category>_2024_</category>
                
                <category>pending</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Mysuru Palace &amp; Vrindavan Gardens</title>
                <description>
</description>
                <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 12:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
                <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/mysuru2</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/mysuru2</guid>
                
                <category>_2024_</category>
                
                <category>bangalore</category>
                
                <category>pending</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>