<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title></title>
        <description></description>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
        <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 09:50:29 +0530</pubDate>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 09:50:29 +0530</lastBuildDate>
        <generator>Jekyll v4.3.3</generator>
        
            <item>
                <title>Hampi</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Exploring Hampi: A Journey of Adventure, Laughter, and Unexpected Surprises&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It had been a while since my last trip outside Bangalore, and with a long weekend approaching, the urge to escape was strong. My friend Mohit and I decided to take a short trip, and after checking with our other college friends (who unfortunately were busy), it was just the three of us—Mohit, his girlfriend Juhi, and me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Journey Begins: A Chaotic Start&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To make the most of our time, we booked an overnight bus from Bangalore to Hampi. The plan was simple: meet up for dinner at HSR Layout, board the bus by 9:00 PM, and wake up in Hospet, the nearest city to Hampi, by 4:00 AM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything was going smoothly until Mohit called me in a panic while I was on my way to deliver a Zoomcar vehicle. We had miscalculated the departure time—the bus was leaving at 9:00 PM, not 10:00 PM! Mohit and Juhi managed to board the bus at Madiwala, but I had to think fast. With just 45 minutes before the bus would reach Anand Rao Circle, I knew a cab wouldn’t cut it in Bangalore’s traffic. I quickly booked a Rapido bike, and thanks to a speedy driver who weaved through the traffic like a pro, I reached the pickup point just in time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The adventure had begun even before we left Bangalore!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Suspicious Encounter at the Bus Station&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Knowing there wouldn’t be any dinner breaks, I decided to use a pay-and-use washroom at the station. As I handed over ₹10 to the attendant, something felt off. Typically, such facilities charge ₹3-₹5. I checked the board outside, but the pricing details were suspiciously covered with paint or stickers. As I kept looking, the attendant got nervous and suddenly called me back, returning ₹5. While I didn’t argue further, it was clear he had been overcharging people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With this little victory, I boarded the bus, settled into my seat, and got comfortable for the journey ahead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reaching Hospet: The Auto Fare Hustle&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bus ride was smooth, and by 4:00 AM, we arrived in Hospet, where we were immediately swarmed by auto drivers. Their initial quotes were ridiculous—₹1000 for a short trip to Hampi, or ₹3500 for a full-day tour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We tried negotiating with a nearby group of four travelers, but they weren’t interested in sharing. One girl rudely dismissed us, saying they had a pre-booked cab. Not letting this dampen our spirits, we finally bargained an auto for ₹500 and reached Hampi in 40 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Matunga Hill: A Breathtaking Sunrise&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our first stop was a small tea stall, where we warmed up with chai in the chilly morning air. The auto driver suggested visiting Malyavanta Hill for sunrise, but after checking Google reviews, we chose Matunga Hill instead—it was closer and had better views.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the base, we met three other travelers, and together, we started our 20-minute hike in total darkness. It was surreal, trying to spot Hampi’s temples just by their silhouettes. Once at the top, we removed our shoes at a small temple and settled in, waiting for the sunrise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The peaceful moment didn’t last long. A chai vendor warned us about the monkeys that would soon arrive looking for food. Right on cue, a troop of them appeared, scanning for unattended bags. One sneaky monkey sat next to my bag, unzipped it, and pulled out my UNO cards! What followed was a chaotic battle of wits, with the monkey determined to escape with its newfound treasure. It even pulled out my toothbrush and shampoo before I managed to snatch the bag back—but not before it ran off with my UNO deck. Everyone burst into laughter at the absurdity of the situation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the sun finally rose, casting golden light over the ancient ruins, we clicked some stunning pictures and soaked in the beauty of Hampi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gallery-box&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;gallery&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/internal/hampi_blog/vlcsnap-2025-03-24-08h59m02s809.png&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;Video Snap 3&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/internal/hampi_blog/vlcsnap-2025-03-24-09h01m55s073.png&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;Video Snap 4&quot; /&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/internal/hampi_blog/IMG_9262.jpg&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;Hampi Image 7&quot; /&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Photos of Matanga hills&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hampi Bazaar and Stone Chariot Temple&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Descending the hill, we got our first proper look at Hampi in daylight. The ancient Hampi Bazaar stretched for half a kilometer, with stone pillars forming what was once a bustling marketplace. Centuries ago, merchants traded everything from diamonds to groceries here—it was fascinating to imagine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We hired an auto for ₹2000 to explore Hampi’s key sites. Our first stop was Vijaya Vittala Temple, home to the famous stone chariot featured on the ₹50 note. On the way, I convinced the auto driver to let me drive, and for 5 km, I took control of the rickshaw, navigating the bumpy roads with glee!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gallery-box&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;gallery&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/internal/hampi_blog/vlcsnap-2025-03-24-09h03m11s287.png&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;Video Snap 5&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/internal/hampi_blog/vlcsnap-2025-03-24-09h05m52s925.png&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;Video Snap 6&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/internal/hampi_blog/DJI_20250315090615_0034_D.JPG&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;Hampi Image 1&quot; /&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Photos of Auto ride&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the temple, we met a Polish traveler who was an avid biker. We bonded over our love for road trips, but since he was heading to Mysore next, our plans didn’t align. After taking the mandatory picture with the stone chariot, we moved on to explore more of Hampi’s royal heritage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;gallery-box&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;gallery&quot;&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/internal/hampi_blog/IMG_9380.jpg&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;Hampi Image 9&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/internal/hampi_blog/IMG_9296.jpg&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;Hampi Image 8&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/internal/hampi_blog/DJI_20250315093040_0045_D.JPG&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;Hampi Image 2&quot; /&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/internal/hampi_blog/IMG_9389.jpg&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;Hampi Image 10&quot; /&gt;

    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Photos of stone chariot&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Dal Disaster and Sunset Serenity&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By midday, exhaustion kicked in, and we stopped at Happy Hampi Café. The restaurant had a unique setup—mattresses on the floor instead of chairs. We lay down, finally getting some rest, when suddenly, chaos struck.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mohit accidentally knocked over a dal container, drenching himself and Juhi in yellow dal. The sight of them, completely covered in dal, had us all in stitches. It took a moment to process what had happened before we burst into uncontrollable laughter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gallery-box&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;gallery&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/internal/hampi_blog/IMG20250315163436.jpg&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;Hampi Image 6&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/internal/hampi_blog/DJI_20250315155550_0077_D.JPG&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;Hampi Image 4&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/internal/hampi_blog/DJI_20250315155707_0079_D.JPG&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;Hampi Image 5&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/internal/hampi_blog/IMG_9475.jpg&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;Hampi Image 11&quot; /&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/internal/hampi_blog/DJI_20250315155331_0074_D.JPG&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;Hampi Image 3&quot; /&gt;

    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Photos of lotus palace&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a good meal and some much-needed downtime, we continued exploring more temples before heading to Tungabhadra Lake for a coracle boat ride.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Initially, we hesitated due to the ₹500 per person charge, but eventually, we went for it. As we paddled across the calm waters, the setting sun cast a golden glow over the landscape. I even got a chance to row the boat, only to realize how physically exhausting it was! Watching the sunset from the middle of the lake, with our hands dipped in the cool water, was the perfect way to end our day in Hampi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gallery-box&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;gallery&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/internal/hampi_blog/vlcsnap-2025-03-24-08h48m26s754.png&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;Video Snap 1&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2025/internal/hampi_blog/vlcsnap-2025-03-24-08h55m09s518.png&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;Video Snap 2&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Photos of boat ride&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wrapping Up: Shopping and the Journey Back&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We stopped at the Hampi market to buy some fridge magnets as souvenirs before heading back to Hospet. Since our bus was at 9:00 PM, we had plenty of time for a leisurely dinner. We tried a nearby ice cream parlor with an overwhelming number of flavor combinations before finally boarding our bus back to Bangalore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By 4:00 AM, we were back in the city, exhausted but happy. Mohit booked a cab, and just like that, our whirlwind trip to Hampi came to an end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Final Thoughts&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From unexpected bus chases to monkey heists and dal disasters, this trip had everything—adventure, history, and laughter. Hampi, with its ancient ruins and surreal landscapes, had given us memories to cherish forever. Until the next adventure!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
                <pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2025 10:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
                <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/hampi</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/hampi</guid>
                
                <category>_2025_</category>
                
                <category>bangalore</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Shri Adinatha Digambara Jaina Basadi (Anivalu)</title>
                <description>
</description>
                <pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2025 10:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
                <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/anivalu-jain-basadi</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/anivalu-jain-basadi</guid>
                
                <category>_2025_</category>
                
                <category>bangalore</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>New Flat Relocation</title>
                <description>
</description>
                <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2025 10:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
                <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/new-flat</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/new-flat</guid>
                
                <category>_2025_</category>
                
                <category>bangalore</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Nandi Hills</title>
                <description>
</description>
                <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2025 06:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
                <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/nandi-hills</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/nandi-hills</guid>
                
                <category>_2025_</category>
                
                <category>bangalore</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Bannerghatta National Park and Benki Falls</title>
                <description>
</description>
                <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 10:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
                <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/bannerghatta-national-park-benki-falls</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/bannerghatta-national-park-benki-falls</guid>
                
                <category>_2025_</category>
                
                <category>bangalore</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Snjana Wedding</title>
                <description>
</description>
                <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 10:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
                <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/sanjana-wedding</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/sanjana-wedding</guid>
                
                <category>_2024_</category>
                
                <category>bangalore</category>
                
                <category>trek</category>
                
                <category>bmw</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Mood Indigo and Zero Latency</title>
                <description>
</description>
                <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 10:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
                <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/mood-indigo-zero-latency</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/mood-indigo-zero-latency</guid>
                
                <category>_2024_</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Sanjana&apos;s Sangeet</title>
                <description>
</description>
                <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 20:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
                <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/sanjana-sangeet</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/sanjana-sangeet</guid>
                
                <category>_2024_</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Mysuru Palace &amp; Vrindavan Gardens</title>
                <description>
</description>
                <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 12:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
                <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/mysuru</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/mysuru</guid>
                
                <category>_2024_</category>
                
                <category>bangalore</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Abbey Waterfall, Coorg</title>
                <description>
</description>
                <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 15:45:00 +0530</pubDate>
                <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/abbey-waterfall</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/abbey-waterfall</guid>
                
                <category>_2024_</category>
                
                <category>bangalore</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>