<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title></title>
        <description></description>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
        <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2024 18:07:13 +0530</pubDate>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2024 18:07:13 +0530</lastBuildDate>
        <generator>Jekyll v4.3.2</generator>
        
            <item>
                <title>Savandurga Trek</title>
                <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;we had to do something on the weekend, so we decided to go for a trek&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;sudhanshu, ujjwal, umakant, anmol, prakhar joined me on the trek&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;a perfect weekend getaway from Bangalore&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Asia’s largest monolith hill&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;we took 5 bikes to reach the base of the hill&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;since this is reserved forest area so we need to book tickets online on karnataka eco tourism website, it costs 300 per person&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;we planned to start by 6 but everone got late and we started by 7&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;we reached the base wher we parked our bikes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gallery-box&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;gallery&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2024/q1/IMG_0363.jpg&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2024/q1/IMG20240420065300.jpg&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2024/q1/IMG_1063.jpg&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Photos of savandurga hill&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;next to the parking there was a small snacks shop which offered us to keep our helmets, heavy jackes and bags for free&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;we reached the starting point where a security guard checked our tickets&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;soon a guide joined us to start the trek&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;at the start of the trek it seemed really easy, but as we moved formwad the trail became steeper&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;we keep on taking brakes and clicked some photos&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;we had several water bottle with us so thankfull we were hydrated&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Anmol brought several snacks which we needed badly during the hike.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;he had a duffel bag with him which had all the snacks and water bottles&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;as the time passed the sun started to shine brightly and it became really hot&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;the landscape was looking very beautiful from the top&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;on our&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gallery-box&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;gallery&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2024/q1/92fffba9-d8f7-4f71-bbc9-1bf52dd808f5.jpg&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2024/q1/IMG_2983.jpeg&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2024/q1/IMG_0384.jpg&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Photos of savandurga hill&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2024 08:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
                <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/savandurga-trek</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/savandurga-trek</guid>
                
                <category>2024</category>
                
                <category>bangalore</category>
                
                <category>trek</category>
                
                <category>bmw</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Skandhagiri Sunrise Trek</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Trekking is a refreshing alternative to the usual weekend routine of getting drunk. After several failed attempts, we finally secured tickets for the highly sought-after sunrise trek near Bangalore, scheduled for March 24th. Our group consisted of Mohit, Shikhar, Nandu, Utkarsh, Siddhi, Hetvee, and myself, all eager for the adventure ahead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Early Start
To ensure an early start, I decided to stay over at Mohit’s place. We needed to be up by 2 AM, so it made sense to minimize travel time in the morning. At 2:30 AM, we set off from Mohit’s place, joined by Shikhar and Utkarsh. Our next stop was Nandu’s house, where Siddhi and Hetvee joined us. By 3 AM, we were on the highway, leaving Bangalore behind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The road was empty and the night sky pitch dark. Our convoy, comprising two cars, one driven by Nandu and the other by Utkarsh, felt like the only souls on the road. We made a quick stop at a roadside Maggi point for some hot Maggi and tea to combat the cold. After a 30-minute break, we resumed our journey and reached the base of the hill by 4 AM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Trek Begins
Upon arrival, we encountered a long queue at the trek’s entry point. It seemed like every adventurer in Bangalore had the same idea. We parked our cars and joined the slow-moving line, eager to start our ascent. Flashlights in hand, we began the trek in the darkness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The initial steep climb left me drenched in sweat and feeling exhausted, but the good news was that the toughest part was over. The path leveled out, making the hike more manageable. I found myself ahead of the group and struck up a conversation with Hetvee, whom I hadn’t met before. The sky began to lighten, signaling that we were nearing the peak.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reaching the Peak
By 5:30 AM, we reached the summit, greeted by a breathtaking sunrise. The view was worth every drop of sweat and every step taken. We spent time capturing the moment with numerous photos. Seeking a moment of solitude, I found a small rock to sit on and take in the stunning scenery. The combination of cold wind and warm sunshine on my face was perfect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After about 30 minutes at the top, we decided to descend. On our way down, we noticed several groups making their way up, confirming our satisfaction with the early start. Among them were two girls who impressively ran down the hill, leaving us in awe of their speed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gallery-box&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;gallery&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2024/q1/IMG_4743.jpeg&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2024/q1/IMG20240324064319.jpg&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2024/q1/IMG20240324062151.jpg&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Photos of Skandhagiri hill&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Return Journey
We descended by 7 AM, feeling sleep-deprived, hungry, and tired. Luckily, there was a small shop at the foothill selling coconut water and snacks. We quenched our thirst with sugarcane juice and coconut water, and grabbed some snacks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point, we realized that Utkarsh was missing. Being new to trekking, he was descending at a slower pace. He caught up with us after about 10 minutes, and we headed back to Bangalore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Initially, we planned to stop for breakfast at a dhaba on the highway. However, everyone fell asleep in the car, so we skipped the plan and drove straight to Mohit’s place. We arrived around 9 AM, and I immediately fell asleep in the hall. I woke up at 11 AM, had some breakfast, and then headed back home.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
                <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2024 02:30:00 +0530</pubDate>
                <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/skandhagiri-trek</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/skandhagiri-trek</guid>
                
                <category>2024</category>
                
                <category>bangalore</category>
                
                <category>trek</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Theralli View Point bike ride and torq</title>
                <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;there was bike rade happedning for royal enfiedl riders, and specialy for hunter riders&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;arun had recently bought a hunter and was excited to participate in the ride&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;i joined arun as a pillion rider&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;we started from royel enfield showroom in whitefield&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;there were 20-25 riders in total&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;we left arounf 6:30 from the showroom&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;weather was good, and the ride was smooth.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;we stopped on our way to have breakfast at Swathi Hotel and Cafe&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;typical south indian breakfast, idli, vada, dosa, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;then we saw a big bikes group also came to the same restaurant.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;the surroundiung was roaring with the sound of bikes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;all liter class bikes, harley davidson, ducati, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;i case ducati panigale v4, kawasaki zx10r, mighy hayabusa, some vintage kawasaki 14xr, and many more.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;i got so excited to see all these bikes, and i was clicking pictures of all the bikes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;we left the restaurant around 8:30&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;our desination was nearby only, theralli view point&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;we reached in 15ish minutes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;the view point was mostly pile of big stoes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;everyone went ahead with the guide, me and arun clumbed a hill of stones and reached the top, clicked some pics there.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;then we came down and went to the view point&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;there were some cases as well.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gallery-box&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;gallery&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2024/q1/IMG20240317081402.jpg&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2024/q1/IMG20240317101718.jpg&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2024/q1/IMG20240317094302.jpg&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Photos of Skandhagiri hill&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;we met our group which was returning from the caves.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;they told us not to go to the caves without a guide.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;we ignored and went to the caves, those were narrow and dusty.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;at some point we had to crawl to go further. then we decided it’s not worth it and came back.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;we went to the view point, clicked some pics there.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;then we started our journey back to bangalore.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;later in the evening, i went to torq with other friends from office.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;we did bowling, go-karting, and some other games.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;we had the most fun doing go-karting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2024 06:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
                <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/theralli-torq</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/theralli-torq</guid>
                
                <category>2024</category>
                
                <category>bangalore</category>
                
                <category>hunter</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>World&apos;s 2nd Highest Bungee</title>
                <description>
</description>
                <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 08:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
                <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/bungee</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/bungee</guid>
                
                <category>2024</category>
                
                <category>nepal</category>
                
                <category>pokhra</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Pokhra, Nepal</title>
                <description>
</description>
                <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 06:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
                <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/pokhra</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/pokhra</guid>
                
                <category>2024</category>
                
                <category>nepal</category>
                
                <category>pokhra</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Mount Everest Flight</title>
                <description>
</description>
                <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 06:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
                <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/mt-everest-flight</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/mt-everest-flight</guid>
                
                <category>2024</category>
                
                <category>nepal</category>
                
                <category>kathmandu</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Kathmandu, Nepal</title>
                <description>
</description>
                <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 06:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
                <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/kathmandu</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/kathmandu</guid>
                
                <category>2024</category>
                
                <category>nepal</category>
                
                <category>kathmandu</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Devrayanadurga Trek</title>
                <description>
</description>
                <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2024 06:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
                <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/devarayanagara-trek</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/devarayanagara-trek</guid>
                
                <category>2024</category>
                
                <category>bangalore</category>
                
                <category>bmw</category>
                
                <category>trek</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Bird Sanctuary - Abondanded Railway Yard</title>
                <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We had a some free time of couple of hours in kochi, so we decided to visit the &lt;a href=&quot;https://maps.app.goo.gl/NtZmadtDkjSbPWfU8&quot;&gt;Mangalavanam Bird Sanctuary&lt;/a&gt;. The sanctuary is a green oasis in the heart of Kochi city. It is a bird sanctuary located in the central part of the city and is easily accessible from the city.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Next to it was a railway yard, which was abandoned. We were curious to see what was inside the yard.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;first we went inside the sanctuary, it was a small sanctuary, nothing much was there, but we saw a DO NOT ENTER sign in the center. After getting close, we realised it s a bird watch tower, makde out of wood, really high. Since we were curious and disobedient, we decided to climb it.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;it must be of a height of 4-5 floors, umkant stood at the base of entrance to watch any guard coming, while ujjwal and I climbed the tower.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;as soon as we climed 1 floor, we realied why it was a DO NOT ENTER zone, the tower was shaking, and we were scared to death. We climbed 3 more floors and reached the top. The view from the top was amazing, we could see the whole sanctuary, its like living in a tree house. completely covered with lush green trees. just like view in waynad, but upclose.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;there was a cctv camera also present on the top. once we stopped climbuing the tower stopped wobbling and we were able to take some good pics.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;while coming down the wooden stares, manager of bird sanctuary came and asked for our tickets. we showed him the tickets. then he asked our id cards, i thought that we are doomed. then he spoke outloud looking at our id cards, “UP, Delhi, MP”. you 3 states are the most mischief makers in the country. we were scared to death, but we laughed a little. we felt sorry(not really) and then he lt us go.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;we roamed around the sanctuary for some time, clicked some pics and went outside.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gallery-box&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;gallery&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2024/2022-06-15.jpg&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2024/IMG20230312165452.jpg&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2024/IMG_20240128_122447.jpg&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Photos of watch tower, and bird santury&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;just at the exit of the bird sanctuary, there was a railway yard, which was abandoned. and ther was a big sign PROTECTED AREA. us being us, we were curious to see what was inside. we went inside the yard.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;it was full of bushes and trees. it was active during the british era, but now it was abandoned. we saw some old tracks, were there.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;after crossing the buses, we saw a old age beautiful building made completly out of stone. it was the structure of railway station. trees were growing out of the building. it was a beautiful sight.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;looking upclose to some wall, it was full of maths equations, we thought it was some students who had written it. but then we realised it was some old railway workers who had written it. maybe some caluclations for the railway or someone might be taking maths classes there.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;next to it were 3 raily lines. they they were not in use since 50-60 year, trees had grown on the tracks.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;we cliked a lot of pics, had a look arounf in the grass, and then we left the place.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;while jumping the fence to exit the yard, we saw the same uncle sitting on the side of exiti with his friends. he saw us and said something to his friend in malayalam, and they laughed. we laughed too. we undestood they were talking about me. and he repeaded again “UP, Delhi, MP” while pointing us in funny way.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;we had a quick chat with him and then left the place. we were happy that we were not caught by the guard. we had a good time in the sanctuary and the railway yard.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gallery-box&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;gallery&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2024/2020-03-01.jpg&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;railway line&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2024/IMG20240128123726.jpg&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;building&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2024/IMG_9922.jpg&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2024/IMG_20240128_124636.jpg&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2024/IMG20240128125141.jpg&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Photos of railway yard&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 13:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
                <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/bird-santuray-railway-yard-copy</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/bird-santuray-railway-yard-copy</guid>
                
                <category>2024</category>
                
                <category>kerela</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Munnar</title>
                <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;150km road trip from kochi to munnar on 2 scooters.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The journey was filled with scenic views, tea plantations, and a buttery smooth ride.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The weather was perfect, and the roads were almost empty.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We stopped at a few places to take pictures and enjoy the view.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;munnar tea plantation was a treat to the eyes, they looked like a green carpet, exactly like the ones we see in movies.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We reached munnar by 2 pm and had some local food.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;we started our journey back to kochi by 4 pm.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gallery-box&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;gallery&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2024/q1/IMG20240127145937.jpg&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2024/q1/IMG_20240127_120646.jpg&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2024/q1/IMG20240127121726.jpg&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Photos of Munnar&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2024 14:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
                <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/munnar</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/munnar</guid>
                
                <category>2024</category>
                
                <category>kerela</category>
                
                <category>munnar</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>