<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title></title>
        <description></description>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
        <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2024 18:46:58 +0530</pubDate>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2024 18:46:58 +0530</lastBuildDate>
        <generator>Jekyll v4.3.2</generator>
        
            <item>
                <title>Savandurga Trek</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, the best way to spend a weekend is by reconnecting with nature and challenging oneself. That’s exactly what we decided to do – embark on a trek to Asia’s largest monolith hill, a perfect weekend escape from the hustle and bustle of Bangalore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our trekking team consisted of Sudhanshu, Ujjwal, Umakant, Anmol, Prakhar, and me. The initial plan was to start our journey at 6 AM, but as it often happens, we got a bit delayed and finally hit the road by 7 AM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Journey Begins
We took five bikes to reach the base of the hill. Since the area is a reserved forest, we had to book our tickets online through the Karnataka Eco Tourism website. The cost was 300 INR per person, which we found reasonable considering the experience that awaited us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Upon reaching the base, we parked our bikes and found a small snack shop nearby. The shop owner kindly offered to keep our helmets, heavy jackets, and bags for free, which was a great relief.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gallery-box&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;gallery&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2024/q1/IMG_0363.jpg&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2024/q1/IMG20240420065300.jpg&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2024/q1/IMG_1063.jpg&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Photos of savandurga hill&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a brief stop at the snack shop, we moved to the starting point of the trek, where a security guard checked our tickets. Soon, a guide joined us to lead the way. The trek began easily enough, but it didn’t take long for the trail to become steeper and more challenging.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We took several breaks along the way, capturing the scenic beauty with our cameras. The importance of staying hydrated during a trek cannot be overstated, and we were well-prepared with several water bottles. Anmol, in particular, was our savior with his duffel bag full of snacks and extra water.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the sun climbed higher in the sky, the heat intensified, making the trek more taxing. Despite the increasing temperature, the beautiful landscape kept us motivated. The view from the top was absolutely breathtaking, making every bit of effort worth it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trekking Asia’s largest monolith hill was an unforgettable experience. It was a perfect mix of adventure, camaraderie, and natural beauty. If you’re looking for a weekend getaway from Bangalore that offers both a physical challenge and stunning vistas, this trek is definitely worth considering. Just remember to book your tickets in advance, pack plenty of water, and bring along good friends to share the journey with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;gallery-box&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;gallery&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2024/q1/92fffba9-d8f7-4f71-bbc9-1bf52dd808f5.jpg&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2024/q1/IMG_2983.jpeg&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2024/q1/IMG_0384.jpg&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Photos of savandurga hill&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2024 08:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
                <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/savandurga-trek</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/savandurga-trek</guid>
                
                <category>2024</category>
                
                <category>bangalore</category>
                
                <category>trek</category>
                
                <category>bmw</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Skandhagiri Sunrise Trek</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Trekking is a refreshing alternative to the usual weekend routine of getting drunk. After several failed attempts, we finally secured tickets for the highly sought-after sunrise trek near Bangalore, scheduled for March 24th. Our group consisted of Mohit, Shikhar, Nandu, Utkarsh, Siddhi, Hetvee, and myself, all eager for the adventure ahead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Early Start
To ensure an early start, I decided to stay over at Mohit’s place. We needed to be up by 2 AM, so it made sense to minimize travel time in the morning. At 2:30 AM, we set off from Mohit’s place, joined by Shikhar and Utkarsh. Our next stop was Nandu’s house, where Siddhi and Hetvee joined us. By 3 AM, we were on the highway, leaving Bangalore behind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The road was empty and the night sky pitch dark. Our convoy, comprising two cars, one driven by Nandu and the other by Utkarsh, felt like the only souls on the road. We made a quick stop at a roadside Maggi point for some hot Maggi and tea to combat the cold. After a 30-minute break, we resumed our journey and reached the base of the hill by 4 AM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Trek Begins
Upon arrival, we encountered a long queue at the trek’s entry point. It seemed like every adventurer in Bangalore had the same idea. We parked our cars and joined the slow-moving line, eager to start our ascent. Flashlights in hand, we began the trek in the darkness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The initial steep climb left me drenched in sweat and feeling exhausted, but the good news was that the toughest part was over. The path leveled out, making the hike more manageable. I found myself ahead of the group and struck up a conversation with Hetvee, whom I hadn’t met before. The sky began to lighten, signaling that we were nearing the peak.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reaching the Peak
By 5:30 AM, we reached the summit, greeted by a breathtaking sunrise. The view was worth every drop of sweat and every step taken. We spent time capturing the moment with numerous photos. Seeking a moment of solitude, I found a small rock to sit on and take in the stunning scenery. The combination of cold wind and warm sunshine on my face was perfect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After about 30 minutes at the top, we decided to descend. On our way down, we noticed several groups making their way up, confirming our satisfaction with the early start. Among them were two girls who impressively ran down the hill, leaving us in awe of their speed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gallery-box&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;gallery&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2024/q1/IMG_4743.jpeg&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2024/q1/IMG20240324064319.jpg&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2024/q1/IMG20240324062151.jpg&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Photos of Skandhagiri hill&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Return Journey
We descended by 7 AM, feeling sleep-deprived, hungry, and tired. Luckily, there was a small shop at the foothill selling coconut water and snacks. We quenched our thirst with sugarcane juice and coconut water, and grabbed some snacks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point, we realized that Utkarsh was missing. Being new to trekking, he was descending at a slower pace. He caught up with us after about 10 minutes, and we headed back to Bangalore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Initially, we planned to stop for breakfast at a dhaba on the highway. However, everyone fell asleep in the car, so we skipped the plan and drove straight to Mohit’s place. We arrived around 9 AM, and I immediately fell asleep in the hall. I woke up at 11 AM, had some breakfast, and then headed back home.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
                <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2024 02:30:00 +0530</pubDate>
                <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/skandhagiri-trek</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/skandhagiri-trek</guid>
                
                <category>2024</category>
                
                <category>bangalore</category>
                
                <category>trek</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Theralli View Point bike ride and torq</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;There was a bike ride happening for Royal Enfield riders, especially for Hunter riders. Arun had recently bought a Hunter and was excited to participate in the ride. I joined Arun as a pillion rider. We started from the Royal Enfield showroom in Whitefield. There were 20-25 riders in total. We left around 6:30 from the showroom. The weather was good, and the ride was smooth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We stopped on our way to have breakfast at Swathi Hotel and Cafe. It was a typical South Indian breakfast with idli, vada, dosa, etc. While we were there, we saw a big group of bikers arrive at the same restaurant. The surroundings roared with the sound of bikes—Harley Davidsons, Ducatis, and other liter-class bikes. I saw a Ducati Panigale V4, a Kawasaki ZX10R, the mighty Hayabusa, some vintage Kawasaki 14XRs, and many more. I got so excited to see all these bikes and clicked pictures of all of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We left the restaurant around 8:30. Our destination was nearby, Theralli View Point, which we reached in about 15 minutes. The viewpoint was mostly a pile of big stones. Everyone went ahead with the guide while Arun and I climbed a hill of stones, reached the top, and clicked some pictures there. Then we came down and went to the viewpoint. There were some caves as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We met our group, who were returning from the caves. They told us not to go to the caves without a guide. Ignoring their advice, we ventured into the caves, which were narrow and dusty. At some points, we had to crawl to go further. Eventually, we decided it wasn’t worth it and came back. We went back to the viewpoint and clicked some more pictures. Then, we started our journey back to Bangalore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;gallery-box&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;gallery&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2024/q1/IMG20240317081402.jpg&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2024/q1/IMG20240317101718.jpg&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2024/q1/IMG20240317094302.jpg&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later in the evening, I went to Torq with other friends from the office. We did bowling, go-karting, and some other games. The most fun was had during go-karting.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
                <pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2024 06:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
                <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/theralli-torq</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/theralli-torq</guid>
                
                <category>2024</category>
                
                <category>bangalore</category>
                
                <category>hunter</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>World&apos;s 2nd Highest Bungee</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Who doesn’t like adventure sports? I have always been a fan of them, but I never thought I would do a bungee jump, especially from the second highest point in the world. The jump was from 228 meters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Me, Om, and Shantanu were in Nepal for a week, and this was on our bucket list. Once we reached Pokhara, we booked a taxi to take us to the bungee location, which was 70 kilometers away and took us three hours to reach. On the way, we saw beautiful landscapes, rivers, and even the Annapurna range. We took a couple of breaks to click pictures and enjoy the view. I had a GoPro with me, recording the whole journey. My stomach was churning with excitement and fear; I wanted to do it, but I was also scared. However, having come this far, I had to go through with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We reached the cliff where the organization managing the bungee jump was located. The entry to the bungee location was through a hanging bridge. At the entry, we did our registration and weight check. The Nepali receptionists were very cute and friendly, making us feel comfortable. We chatted with them, and they told us they had been doing this for years. We packed our bags, kept them in the locker, and headed towards the bridge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Walking towards the jump point was thrilling. The bridge was hanging over a river, and the jump was from the bridge, which connected two mountains forming a 300-meter deep valley. Almost in the middle of the valley was the jump point. Initially, walking on the rope bridge was scary, but as we reached the middle, it wasn’t that scary, and the view was getting better and better. The jump point was a small platform with eight guys managing the jump.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were in the first batch, so as a customary practice, one of the instructors jumped first to check the rope and the entire setup. Nobody had ever died here, but it was still a good practice. He showed some stunts while going down. Om was the first one to jump; he was excited and scared at the same time. Watching people jump from the bridge was also thrilling. The jump was so fast that it was over in a blink of an eye.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gallery-box&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;gallery&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2024/q1/parash.00_00_26_37.Still003.jpg&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2024/q1/IMG_9430.jpg&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2024/q1/IMG_9476.jpg&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2024/q1/IMG_9507.jpg&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2024/q1/IMG_9546.jpg&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2024/q1/IMG_9520.jpg&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was my turn now. I was scared but also excited. They tied a camera on my hand and did some pre-checks. The harness was tight, and I was placed near the edge of the platform. When I looked down from the jumping point, my blood froze, and I felt my heart skip a beat. Zero thoughts, just the feeling of falling. When you can see your death, you feel alive. I knew the harness would save me, but the feeling of falling was still there. The instructor said some motivational words to make me feel comfortable, but I wasn’t listening; I was just looking down. Then I thought, I have come so far; I’m not going to back out now. I took a deep breath and jumped.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh boy, the feeling of free-falling was amazing. The wind was gushing through my hair, and the view was spectacular. The adrenaline rush was real. I was falling at 120 km/h. The fall lasted for 3-4 seconds but felt like eternity. I was screaming, shouting, laughing, and crying all at the same time. The feeling of falling was so amazing that I wanted to do it again. The jump lasted 8-9 seconds before the rope pulled me back up. It is an elastic rope, so I was bouncing up and down for some time. Since you fall upside down, the valley with the river at the bottom looked even more beautiful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I opened my eyes and saw the camera, doing some vlogging. They pulled me back up, and I was so happy that I did it. I was so proud of myself. Best 10k spent so far. It took me some time to realize that I did it. I went out of the jump platform. Since Om and I were done, we started clicking pictures. Being overweight, Shantanu was last in the queue. We went to get snacks and drinks. Shantanu also did the jump, and it was fun. We were so happy that we did it. We took some more pictures and then left for Pokhara.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 08:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
                <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/bungee</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/bungee</guid>
                
                <category>2024</category>
                
                <category>nepal</category>
                
                <category>pokhra</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Pokhra, Nepal</title>
                <description>
</description>
                <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 06:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
                <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/pokhra</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/pokhra</guid>
                
                <category>2024</category>
                
                <category>nepal</category>
                
                <category>pokhra</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Mount Everest Flight</title>
                <description>
</description>
                <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 06:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
                <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/mt-everest-flight</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/mt-everest-flight</guid>
                
                <category>2024</category>
                
                <category>nepal</category>
                
                <category>kathmandu</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Kathmandu, Nepal</title>
                <description>
</description>
                <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 06:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
                <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/kathmandu</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/kathmandu</guid>
                
                <category>2024</category>
                
                <category>nepal</category>
                
                <category>kathmandu</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Devrayanadurga Trek</title>
                <description>
</description>
                <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2024 06:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
                <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/devarayanagara-trek</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/devarayanagara-trek</guid>
                
                <category>2024</category>
                
                <category>bangalore</category>
                
                <category>bmw</category>
                
                <category>trek</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Bird Sanctuary - Abondanded Railway Yard</title>
                <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We had a some free time of couple of hours in kochi, so we decided to visit the &lt;a href=&quot;https://maps.app.goo.gl/NtZmadtDkjSbPWfU8&quot;&gt;Mangalavanam Bird Sanctuary&lt;/a&gt;. The sanctuary is a green oasis in the heart of Kochi city. It is a bird sanctuary located in the central part of the city and is easily accessible from the city.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Next to it was a railway yard, which was abandoned. We were curious to see what was inside the yard.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;first we went inside the sanctuary, it was a small sanctuary, nothing much was there, but we saw a DO NOT ENTER sign in the center. After getting close, we realised it s a bird watch tower, makde out of wood, really high. Since we were curious and disobedient, we decided to climb it.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;it must be of a height of 4-5 floors, umkant stood at the base of entrance to watch any guard coming, while ujjwal and I climbed the tower.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;as soon as we climed 1 floor, we realied why it was a DO NOT ENTER zone, the tower was shaking, and we were scared to death. We climbed 3 more floors and reached the top. The view from the top was amazing, we could see the whole sanctuary, its like living in a tree house. completely covered with lush green trees. just like view in waynad, but upclose.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;there was a cctv camera also present on the top. once we stopped climbuing the tower stopped wobbling and we were able to take some good pics.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;while coming down the wooden stares, manager of bird sanctuary came and asked for our tickets. we showed him the tickets. then he asked our id cards, i thought that we are doomed. then he spoke outloud looking at our id cards, “UP, Delhi, MP”. you 3 states are the most mischief makers in the country. we were scared to death, but we laughed a little. we felt sorry(not really) and then he lt us go.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;we roamed around the sanctuary for some time, clicked some pics and went outside.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gallery-box&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;gallery&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2024/2022-06-15.jpg&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2024/IMG20230312165452.jpg&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2024/IMG_20240128_122447.jpg&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Photos of watch tower, and bird santury&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;just at the exit of the bird sanctuary, there was a railway yard, which was abandoned. and ther was a big sign PROTECTED AREA. us being us, we were curious to see what was inside. we went inside the yard.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;it was full of bushes and trees. it was active during the british era, but now it was abandoned. we saw some old tracks, were there.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;after crossing the buses, we saw a old age beautiful building made completly out of stone. it was the structure of railway station. trees were growing out of the building. it was a beautiful sight.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;looking upclose to some wall, it was full of maths equations, we thought it was some students who had written it. but then we realised it was some old railway workers who had written it. maybe some caluclations for the railway or someone might be taking maths classes there.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;next to it were 3 raily lines. they they were not in use since 50-60 year, trees had grown on the tracks.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;we cliked a lot of pics, had a look arounf in the grass, and then we left the place.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;while jumping the fence to exit the yard, we saw the same uncle sitting on the side of exiti with his friends. he saw us and said something to his friend in malayalam, and they laughed. we laughed too. we undestood they were talking about me. and he repeaded again “UP, Delhi, MP” while pointing us in funny way.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;we had a quick chat with him and then left the place. we were happy that we were not caught by the guard. we had a good time in the sanctuary and the railway yard.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gallery-box&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;gallery&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2024/2020-03-01.jpg&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;railway line&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2024/IMG20240128123726.jpg&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;building&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2024/IMG_9922.jpg&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2024/IMG_20240128_124636.jpg&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2024/IMG20240128125141.jpg&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Photos of railway yard&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 13:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
                <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/bird-santuray-railway-yard-copy</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/bird-santuray-railway-yard-copy</guid>
                
                <category>2024</category>
                
                <category>kerela</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Munnar</title>
                <description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;150km road trip from kochi to munnar on 2 scooters.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The journey was filled with scenic views, tea plantations, and a buttery smooth ride.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The weather was perfect, and the roads were almost empty.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We stopped at a few places to take pictures and enjoy the view.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;munnar tea plantation was a treat to the eyes, they looked like a green carpet, exactly like the ones we see in movies.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We reached munnar by 2 pm and had some local food.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;we started our journey back to kochi by 4 pm.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gallery-box&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;gallery&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2024/q1/IMG20240127145937.jpg&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2024/q1/IMG_20240127_120646.jpg&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/2024/q1/IMG20240127121726.jpg&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Photos of Munnar&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2024 14:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
                <link>http://localhost:4000/blog/munnar</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/blog/munnar</guid>
                
                <category>2024</category>
                
                <category>kerela</category>
                
                <category>munnar</category>
                
                
            </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>